uh this is a quick little update video
as you know I change my mind all the
time I stopped doing things that I said
I was going to do another let me catch
you up so a lot of you have been really
sad because I said I was going to stop
doing the Cod Mage book and here's the
thing I've always wanted to do the code
Mage book and the terminal velocity book
actually unlocked the code Mage book
again let me let me explain why so the
reason my Envision for the Cod made book
always was a book with really pretty
illustrations that was designed for
somebody as young as 10 even nine
depending on if they can read and how
how young they are and it's going to be
ridiculously simple and small it's going
to be mostly pretty pictures but it's
going to teach the fundamentals of
computer science and practical
programming with go as a first language
but it's going to be ridiculously simple
and it's not going to have go routines
in there other than in a very very very
simp I don't even know if I can get them
in there so concurrency is a basic thing
of computer science can I teach it to a
10-year-old I think I probably can and
we think it probably will be in the form
of like wandering monsters that's what
we actually did in our game and then we
hit a problem is we couldn't teach
wandering monsters without concurrency
because you need a loop running all the
time that's like deciding whether a
Wandering monster comes in or you get
eaten by a
grw uh or stuff so the Cod Mage book is
coming back and it will it will be back
but when it comes back this as of this
this moment it's going to be only go
it's not going to cover anything about
the terminal at all it'll have maybe one
page of here's some go here's some
methods for editing that you can go look
at and one of them will be a link to
what I'm working on right now which is
the terminal velocity book so the
terminal velocity book boost your coding
hacking and learning to the pastest
human computer interface speed and that
that that has been
quite frankly overwhelmingly the most
requested thing on all of my live
streams everybody wants to get I mean
really good with the terminal this
includes go programming and that
confuses some people it confused me at
first because I was like okay I want to
teach people how to program go on the
terminal and then I started realizing
you can't really do that until they hit
about 13 or so I mean you can but yeah I
have done it I've done it with the
9-year-old but you know and some things
Chang in the terminal velocity book you
see the ages here
this is all rendered by the way on uh
RBX rob.
github.io books if you go out there um
you can go see the latest
anytime um and so you know here here you
go here's here's a fancier version of
it um it looks like I haven't committed
it with the I move the I move the ages
up over here let me show you I haven't
looks like I think let me just go get it
back here so yeah here we go I haven't
committed it yet so so here this is the
this is the this is the new version that
you'll see um so again the code M book
is designed for T it up which frees me
up to do only like really rudimentary
things and I seriously it's it's
probably only going to be maybe 50 pages
of really really pretty pretty text and
it's going to have like really really
simple examples in big old font with
lots of color um so that we can do that
hey Bobby so that is still on the table
so if those of you who have been
saddened that I'm not covering uh
beginning programming um just know that
I'm still doing it I just I need to get
to the other stuff first um I did spend
some time organizing the books in the
order of age and this this was a real
Revelation to me the whole entire time I
have been flustered by the fact that I
have been writing for different age
groups with different access it's so
funny on Silicon ballet yesterday my
wife are re rewatching series and um
they had the they had the episode where
denesh is the new CEO and he uh releases
this really awesome video platform with
no terms of service and he ends up
almost you know paying 26 billion dollar
for Copa violation child online
protection act ends up getting out of it
by selling it to Gavin bson and forcing
him to you know swallow the pill I don't
want to make a book that's in violation
of the child online protection agreement
but that encourages people to do that
and when I was doing the first code Mage
book I ran into that problem about in
the middle of it because I had at the
time I had a Hardline requirement for
GitHub and GitHub is a you have to be 13
or older just like any online service
and um that tanked uh my
organization because um yeah
so the problem with that is that first
of all I started saying okay I decided
to change it by making this Kitty book
with you know illustrations in childish
language childlike how about that to uh
to be for 13-year-olds and then I
started realizing 13-year-olds aren't
going to put up with this you know baby
stuff this stuff talking to about Harry
Potter and all that that they're not
that's not going to appeal to them that
appeals to somebody who's still playing
Minecraft and
Roblox honestly I know that's I don't
mean to insult young people but I've
been around them long enough to know
there they have a certain tolerance for
certain at the same time they stop
watching cartoons and start watching
things that have real people in them um
you know and I actually did a whole bit
of research this last two weeks ago
actually about you know ages and stuff
anyway so now that I know that the code
makes for fill book is going to just be
install vs code have your mom or dad
help you install vs code have your mom
or dad help you uh set up your terminal
if you're older if you're reading this
and then we're just going to it's it's
just going to be go code only it's just
going to be go code it's going to be go
code and lots of pictures and it's not
it's going to not make any assumptions
about your environment it's like you
need to get your environment up okay now
go compile it and run it and we'll cover
how to compile and run which has to be
done from the command line you cannot do
that without that but we probably that
book will probably be taught from using
BS code and the reason for that is
because an AB absolute beginner like an
absolute total beginner uh that's what
they're going to have that's what the
school is going to give them they're not
going to have something beside the other
thing that's really great about vs code
is it's so easy to play with the colors
I've noticed this with really young
people they'll they'll start at vs code
and they'll they'll change their colors
they have like 10 10 different themes so
they can pick their own theme and play
with it and everything they don't have
to learn how to you know configure West
term and all that jazz there's no
westerm at all period there is there is
no they use the terminal that's built in
BS scope so
um so the code M for spell book is going
to use a graphical editor it's going to
be uh if you want to use the terminal
you can but the assumption is that
you're using BS code and and then um and
then you know you guys can like you know
trash on me for for recommending BS Cod
to microsof I don't care I don't care
we're not even going to do BS codium
because the school districts are going
to adopt it or going to be using vs code
uh vs Cod is not as safe as vs code I'm
going to stand by that uh vscodium a lot
of people don't know chromium chromium
had a really serious security flaw in it
for a year because nobody saw it because
all the attention was on Chrome itself
so I still think Chrome is a better web
browser uh than chromium uh you can
fight me on that I don't care um that's
the way we're going so um so that's
what's going on autodidactic is actually
really really important that I finish
this one too so I've decided this to be
12 and up this is after you are um using
the techniques uh to to learn and
process critical information thinking
we're going to teach you you know things
like blooms taxonomy how to learn all of
that um how to take notes um you know
we'll start by taking notes in in um uh
you know just just showing you how you
can take notes on a USB stick and
everything we're not going to have any
any GitHub in there yet uh I Ser I
thought about maybe making autodidactic
into a 13 and up and it might still be
um because because you know you're 13
you can put GitHub in there um the other
thing that's really great about that
with vs code is that you just click on a
button and it automatically syns to get
up so you there's going to be people in
here they going to yell at me they're
the terminality people like why are you
doing that because they're young they're
just starting out and yes it's true they
can learn the terminal but you know a
lot of the teachers don't know the
terminal are going to be using the book
and the parents so they're going to have
much greater easier deal of it
introducing it and then and when they
get to terminal velocity which is the
big one this is probably my biggest book
um this has got the coding hacking
learning and this is everything and so
actually some really cool things about
this um that I want to introduce today I
didn't make a video about this yet but
I'm going to so there's the regular
introduction um and um and I'm actually
going to go through this in the holiday
boost a little bit later but um so it
has the whole hackers way thing so this
is a book that's written for
13-year-olds that's designed for people
who can have GitHub and giab access even
though we're not going to rely on GitHub
at first we're going to teach you how to
do it if you want to be a hacker and
don't want to have anybody know what
you're doing we're going to show you how
to do that how to manage it all on your
own so find a mentor all this other
stuff so but this is still this is the
big one this is you know targeted at at
people who are uh you know interested in
hacking usually about 13 and then okay
so this entire section is new I didn't
do a video on this yet but this is
really big deal this actually I I need
to write a book about this discovery um
or at least a booklet so the code is
your documentation so one of the things
that I've been struggling with on on all
of this is how to organize all the
complexity of learning what to learn
when to learn it if you need to learn it
how do you learn it um how do we
maintain that level of customization and
flexibility without losing you and the
answer is you know the same thing as um
as code like write a script so execute
this so this is this this isn't done at
all I've been in the middle of doing
this all week um this is your code this
is the code this is a
flowchart code is just a flowchart in
fact I'm I really am looking forward to
making a tool that actually parses bash
is what this is you're like why bash
well because bash is readable python is
readable but it's also screwed up
because it has whites space indentation
and that's not implied people don't
won't won't it's just much harder to Gro
as an absolute beginner it's easier to
write literate programming kind of
things using bash than anything else
because it's the highest level language
you're ever going to use the high is way
higher than python so we're going to
write that so I write the script of what
you need to do next in bash this is up
right now you can actually go look at
this so uh last time we did a thing
about well what are you you know what
are you going to learn next how do you
learn it and this is ever evolving but
this this is you know check that you
have the prerequisites set up your
terminal Workstation use the basic
terminal commands this this stuff down
here needs to change the Pearl stuff
needs to be Consolidated you start using
basic terminal use a web from the
terminal uh connect with others and
terminal lovers that's through IRC or
whatever anyway so each one of these
steps is broken down just like code into
its own thing start using PE from the
CLI that's the one I've added uh by the
way we definitely need to learn Pearl in
fact we're by organizing my thoughts
this way I realized that one of the core
tools that I use with Bim all the time
is Pearl command command line Pearl so
we're going to do it and and I'm going
to justify that statement there's going
to be people that are going to trash on
this because I said you need to learn
Pearl in 2024 if you're not learning
Pearl in 2024 you're an idiot if you
think set and a is going to cover what
Pearl can
cover you really don't know what you're
talking about at all and I'm going to
show you I'm going to justify that
conclusion so stay tuned um there's some
things you can do with th that I just
did today actually while I was writing
the book that you just a would just know
it's just not happening plus it's like
basic regex anyway I don't want to
justify that this this there's a lot of
stuff here and now this is when I
realized because you know this continues
to break down all the steps break down
the steps break down the steps set up W
term do this BL blah so so this is how
the terminal velocity book is taking
form uh it's actually the first book
that I'm going to write where the at
least one section of the book is going
to be Cod it's going to be a flow chart
and it's going to be go to this and then
go to this um which is really
interesting because I've actually been
using the bash interpreter uh to catch
my
mistakes so the bash interpreter catches
my logic blow mistakes it catches it you
know it catches like this was not called
it's super great for like writing flows
and I already had one other educator say
that they are going to steal this and
start doing that to break down their own
uh curriculum the flow of their of their
curriculum so I'm super excited about
that I think it needs to be written okay
a couple other books here home labet I I
am going to do this I don't know how
much of this I'm going to do um you know
when I when I work on a thing I document
it and I put it in here like how to set
up my prox which I need to reset up by
the way before we get too much farther
along uh I did start another book goolan
GES um and I got this I started this
book because um of this gotcha so this
is a Golan
gotcha very simple thing
but don't do this don't pass the string
at it's very you know humble thing like
why would you not pass like I'm passing
the string at first and the string
should go after that so as like this is
why you don't because it makes it
incompatible with goling templates this
is very very very very lowlevel esoteric
goang kind of stuff but it will prevent
you a lot of pain and heartache and it's
a collection of things as they happen to
me that have happened to me over time so
that's that's what that's about um and
the bad span OB biscuit shut shut the
back up and they're never roing these
are all adult books um these are over 18
and actually that's one of the reasons I
put the the age on here because I
realize that as a public Persona I need
to kind of compartmentalize and I I
should at least put age appropriate
stuff here a lot of you don't know that
know that my YouTube I try to be age
appropriate um my live streams very
clearly are never age appropriate they
are you know adult because I am speaking
like an adult in a in a way
my holiday boost videos and stuff like
this generally are rated PG so 13 and
over
um uh okay so yeah I'm putting a lot of
effort into this my wife and I had to
talk and I'll just wrap up with this my
wife and I had to talk over coffee this
morning and you know we were just
realizing how many things in the world
that people might be capable of doing
but they don't do
it um and
you know there are the people who are
capable and don't do it for because of
life or whatever and then there are
people who are just not capable of
making you know five 300 Page books or
whatever or even one 300 Page book and
they just don't have it in them to go
all the way to the end of it and I
definitely do but but I am not going to
do it again I was emboldened by Gil foil
on Silicon Valley who says you know I
don't I don't put crap out you know he's
they're trying to work on the box and he
it's up making his algorithm too fast
because he can't he just refuses to do
you know bad stuff and that goes that
goes for me and my problem is the reason
I I don't finish stuff is because it
takes me so long to do thing uh oh one
other thing I wanted you to notice that
I started adding descriptions to my to
my videos and they're 100% AI generated
it's absolutely amazing uh you know
everybody has suggested to me that I get
a an adult to help me or something and I
I'm going to make a video just about
that so the way you do it is you you
download the um use utdl to get the
transcript and then you send the
transcript to your AI and then the AI
summarizes it and I asked her to put it
in first person as if I was talking and
and then she put chapter headings in in
the description automatically based on
the change in tone and the change in
Topic in the video by itself and it took
me all of five minutes to go through an
entire 6-hour video provide a summarized
description with chapter
markers people I I I'm I want to keep
saying this because I would be remiss if
I had any video on YouTube that didn't
mention how important it is that you
start leveraging AI in your life today
and I'm not just talking about coding
I'm talking about anything and
everything if you don't do it you're
going to get left behind and I'll end on
that